埃尔  和我们想的一样
Al, it's what we thought.
好  我们怎么办
All right, what are we going to do?
在这里等着
Wait it out.
也许能和琳德赛取得联络
Probably get in touch with Lindsey.
提醒她一下
Give her a head's up.
不会有事的  汉克
It's going to be okay, Hank.
我做了我该做的
Did what I had to do.
安东尼奥  很高兴见到你  朋友
Antonio, good to see you, my friend.
我也是  马可  这是我的搭档  金
Good to see you too, Marco. Hey, this is my partner, Kim.
我们俩是在几年前我在10局
We met years ago when I walked the foot post
跑腿的时候认识的
here in the 10th district.
-有什么事吗  -那天晚上
- So what can I do for you? - The other night,
有几个混蛋闯了进来  砸了我的店
some animal broke into my shop and trashed the place.
你向分局报警了吗
Did you report it to the district?
他们要我去搞监控录像
They told me to get surveillance cameras.
我就搞了
So I did.
结果昨晚  我关门后
Then last night, after I closed up,
有个小混蛋骑着自行车
some punk kid rode up on a bike,
要我给他老大交保护费
told me bad things would happen
否则不会有好果子吃
unless I paid his boss protection money.
-你怎么和他说的  -我要他去死
- What did you tell him? - Told him to go to hell.
我给他看了看这个
And I showed him this.
马可  你干什么
Hey, hey, Marco, what are you doing?
放心  我有持枪许可
Relax, I've got a permit.
那不是重点
That's not the point.
你以为我会被几个小孩子吓到吗
You think I'm going to let some kid shake me down?
我知道  但是你得让我们来处理
I get it, but you need to let us take care of this.
你认识这个孩子吗
Do you know this kid?
-从来没见过  -好的
- Never saw him before. - All right.
我找人谈谈  我会查清楚怎么回事
Let me talk to a few people, I'll see what's going on.
然后我们明早在你开店之前
And then we'll swing by the shop tomorrow morning
来找你一趟  我们会查清楚的
before you open, and we'll figure something out.
-没错  -好吗
- Yeah. - Okay?
-把枪放在家里  -好的
- Leave that at home. - I will.
-谢谢  -没事
- And thank you. - Yeah.
谢谢
Okay, thanks.
帮派调查组说26帮和王者帮
So, gang investigation says the 26ers and the Kings
原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
都是在10区的大帮派
are big dogs in the 10th district.
但是他们一般不勒索别人  所以...
But extortion isn't their thing, so...
马可在那里住了30多年
Well, Marco's been in that neighborhood for 30 years.
翻译     小酸奶   风城章鱼X   Lynn_宁   H小欠
大家都不会去招惹他
People know not to mess with him.
可能只是几个混小子
It's probably just some wannabe kids
想搞点钱
trying to make a quick buck.
翻译     小萝莉   不高兴童鞋   圈圈
10辖区各巡逻队  芝加哥各巡逻队
Units in the 10th district and units on the citywide,
接到报警称发生多次枪击
we have an unknown number of shots fired,
校对     圈圈
18街2553号
2553 18th Street.
-请前往调查  -那是马可的店
- Responding units advise. - That's Marco's shop.
时间轴     chance-coco   西查
-他做了什么  -5021E队
- What the hell did he do? - 50-21 Eddie squad,
报告  便衣接警  正在前往
be advised plain clothes units responding
18街枪击发生地
to that shots fired on 18th.
后期     8T
总监     圈圈
-去后门  -收到
- Take the back! - Copy.
-从右边上  -嗯
- Go right. - Yep.
-正在打开后门  -好
- Opening the back door. - Okay.
安全吗
Clear?
马可
Marco.
上帝啊  上帝啊
Oh, man. Oh, man.
杀戮
恐吓
控制[西班牙语]
安东尼奥
Antonio.
上帝啊
Oh, God.
芝加哥
警署
第五季
第十三集
我知道  我知道  外面搜过了吗
I got it, I got that. Did you get the outside?
什么情况
All right, what do we got?
死者名叫马可·里维拉  这家店是他的
DOA is Marco Rivera, He owned the place.
安东尼奥和我昨晚和他说过话
Antonio and I talked to him last night.
他说有本地帮派在找他要保护费
Said a local gang was shaking him down for protection money.
我们找到了一名证人
We did find one witness.
他说有两名凶犯  西班牙裔  从后面跑了
He said two male offenders, Hispanic, ran out the back,
但是没看清楚脸
but didn't get a good look at their faces.
马可回击了几枪
Marco managed to get off a couple of shots,
但是好像没有打中人
but it doesn't look like he hit anyone.
-乔  -汉克
- Hey, Joe. - Hank.
这是马赛拉·戈麦斯警探
Detective Marcella Gomez,
萨尔瓦多国家警察
national civil police of El Salvador.
她是来监察芝加哥警局办案的
She's here observing how the CPD homicide does business.
-很高兴认识你  -安东尼奥·道森警探
- Pleasure. - Detective Antonio Dawson.
这是我的搭档  金
This is my partner, Kim.
-你好  -这些词呢
- Hi. - So these words?
杀戮  恐吓  控制
Kill, terrify, control.
这是萨尔瓦多黑帮的座右铭
The motto for the Salvadoran gang.
西卡瑞奥萨维斯帮  SS11
Sicarios Savios, SS-11.
你在你们那儿接触过他们的案子吗
You've worked some of these cases back home?
不少
Several.
很遗憾  这起案子和那些案子差不多
And sadly, they all look a lot like this.
所以说他们喜欢用刀子
So they like knives, huh?
弯刀
Machetes.
他们以恐吓出名  所以他们下手动静很大
Their brand is intimidation, so they come out big.
手段极其残忍
Make the murders as gruesome as possible.
不管怎么样  乔
Anyway, Joe.
安东尼本来就在处理
Antonio was working an extortion angle
死者被勒索的案子  我们想接手这个案子
with this victim. We'd like to run with the case.
没问题  随时告诉我们进度
No problem, just keep us in the loop.
谢谢  很高兴见到你们
Thanks a lot. Nice to meet you.
我想来帮忙  如果你们愿意的话
I'd be happy to help out, if you want.
我很了解他们的作案手法
I know how they operate very good.
-你来决定  乔  -我没有意见
- Well, that's your call, Joe. - Fine by me.
好  那欢迎加入
Great. All right, welcome aboard.
他们是很坏的人
These are very bad people.
我听说他们对马可做的事了  大家都听说了
I heard what they did to Marco. Everyone has.
-我们能保护你  -是吗
- We can protect you. - Can you?
我的孩子  我的妻子呢
And my kids, and my wife?
对不起  但我得为我的家人
Look, I'm sorry, but I've got to do
做我该做的事
what's best for my family.
至少告诉我们他们长什么样吧
At least tell us what they look like.
他们有什么特别的地方吗
Was there anything distinct about them?
那些来收钱的都只是孩子
The ones who collect, they're just kids.
但只要我付钱不及时  就会有三个大人找我
But once I was late to pay, and three older men came.
他们警告我如果敢报警
They warned me that if I went to the police,
他们就会杀了我
that they were going to kill me,
还有我的家人
and my family.
其中一个是领头的  脸上全是文身
One was the boss, he had tattoos all over his face.
是两个字母S
Um, the letters "SS,"
旁边是一个拳头伸出两根手指
next to a fist with two fingers extended.
谢谢  如果有什么需要  就联系我们
Thank you, if you need anything, you call us.
才怪
Hell no.
他们还算聪明
They know better than to
知道不来我弗兰尼的店里抢钱
come into Franny's place looking to get paid.
好吧  那最近呢
Okay, but how about recently?
有人到你们店里找事吗
Anybody coming in here and messing with the store?
前几天晚上有人试过要闯进来
Someone tried to break in a couple nights back,
打碎了个窗户  被警报吓退了
Broke a window. Alarm scared him off.
我都没打算叫你们
I didn't bother calling y'all.
那弗兰尼女士  你应该知道
Well, Ms. Franny, you should probably know
他们一定会再回来的
that they'll definitely be back.
索要保护费
Demanding protection money.
你认为就是他们杀了马可吗
You think they're the ones who killed Marco?
是
Yes, ma'am.
他是我当年刚刚开张时
He was the first person to come down
第一个来店里欢迎我搬进来的人
and welcome me to the block when I opened my store.
那好  也许你应该帮助我们
All right, so, maybe help us out.
我会尽量帮助你们的
I'll help you however I can.
那好  谢了  弗兰尼女士
All right, thank you, Ms. Franny.
-多谢了  -谢谢你的松饼
- Appreciate you. - And thank you for the muffin.
不客气
You're welcome.
面部识别看来是不行了
So much for facial rec.
倒回去  到进门时停下
Go back and freeze it in the doorway.
放大到左面那个人的手上
Zoom in on the hands of the guy on the left.
把那个文身截图
Get those tats.
另一个人额头上的文身也截一下
And do the same on the forehead for the other guy.
这些文身挺独特的
Those are pretty unique.
我们那边有个SS-11文身的数据库
We have a database of SS-11 tattoos back home.
我能让我的人查一查这几个文身都是谁的
I can have my people try and put a name to those images.
好
Yeah.
好  切到室内摄像头吧
All right, let's switch to the inside camera.
我去吧  你继续看
I got her. You keep watching.
不好意思
Oh. I'm sorry.
-天啊  -你还好吗
- Jesus. - Hey, you okay?
我不知道我这是怎么了
I don't know what's wrong with me.
你没怎么
Nothing.
真相就是  想不让那种景象
The truth is, it's a bigger problem
影响到你  是很难的
if stuff like that doesn't get to you.
给
Here.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我不知道该怎么看待一个
I don't know what to think about a guy
随身携带纸巾的男的
who carries tissues in his jacket.
也许他是个感情丰富的人
Well, he's either incredibly sensitive,
又或者他可能感冒了  又或者
or he's got a cold. Or he's...
他是为了应对芝加哥的寒冬
Prepared for winter in Chicago.
我猜你大概是以上三种可能都有吧
Well, I'm going to guess all of the above.
谢谢
Thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
安保录像有什么收获吗
Anything from the security footage?
看不清脸  但确实截到了几个独特的文身
No faces, but we did capture some unique tats
在他们的手上和额头上
on their hands and forehead.
正在我们和全国的数据库中进行比对
Checking our databases and around the country.
马赛拉已经把图片
Marcella sent the images
发回在萨尔瓦多的局里
back to her department in El Salvador.
如果他们在萨尔瓦多被捕
If they were arrested in El Salvador,
这些帮派文身就会进入我们的数据库
those gang tattoos will be in our system.
有当地人站出来提供情报了吗
Any locals willing to get involved?
有  我们还真找到个
Oh, yeah, we actually got
挺厉害的面包店主弗兰尼
a badass bakery owner named Franny.
她说我们可以随意用她的店
She said we can use her store to do anything we want.
还没有帮派找她的麻烦
She hasn't been approached by the gang yet,
但她的店几天前被人破坏过
but her store was vandalized a few days ago,
所以如果按照他们的套路
so if they follow the pattern,
很快他们就会再去找她麻烦
they should be hitting her up soon.
他们会先派一个收账人去要个价
They'll send in a chequeo to make the initial offer.
-收账人  -是  一个青少年
- Chequeo? - Yes, a teenager.
他们利用一个青少年网络
They use a network of young kids
在街头传递消息
to deliver messages from the street.
给帮派头目
To and from the gang leaders.
不用手机
No phones.
收账人进店之后
When the chequeo comes into the store,
我们让店主拒绝付钱
we have the owner refuse to pay.
然后我们尽量跟着收账人
And then we try our best to tail the chequeos
-回到帮派的安全屋  -好
- back to the gang's safe house. - Hmm.
希望能追查到老大
And hopefully the boss.
抱歉打断一下  汉克  借一步说话
I'm sorry to interrupt, Hank. I need a word.
听上去不错  就按她说的来
That sounds good. Let's do it her way.
-布置下去吧  -用我的办公桌吧
- Set it up. - Use my desk.
丹尼
Denny?
超级玛刚刚动工要开新店
Super Mart just broke ground on a new store.
就在22号大街路桥边上
Over on that old railroad property
那一片临铁道地块上
down by the 22nd street bridge.
昨天工程被叫停了
Yesterday, construction was halted.
建筑工发现了一些人体遗骨
The builders uncovered some human remains.
是  我听说了
Yeah, I read about that.
法医检测出了一个匹配身份
Well, a medical examiner just made a positive ID.
凯文·宾汉姆
It's Kevin Bingham.
你儿子的杀手
The man who murdered your son.
你失去儿子已经很难过了
I mean, losing your boy is hard enough,
但还要让你的名字经受这么多议论
but to have your name dragged in the mud like that?
内务部的人正在仓库里调查
Internal Affairs out there digging around the silos,
寻找宾汉姆的遗体
looking for Bingham's body.
还指控你杀了他
Accusing you of murdering him.
那真是
That's...
真的很难接受
That's a lot to take.
我经受得住
I got thick skin.
是  我想让你知道
Yeah, well, I want you to know that crime lab
取证室在处理这件事  加班加点为你正名
is all over this, working overtime to clear your name.
我很感谢
I appreciate that.
我想在地里埋了这么久
I figure all this time in the ground,
很难找到能给我
it's going to be tough to find something
正名的东西了
to clear my name.
再看吧
We'll see about that.
我调了联调局的一队法医来帮忙
I brought in an FBI forensics team to help out.
我们一起应对  汉克
It's all hands on deck, Hank.
你经历了这么多  这是我们至少能做的
It's the least we could do for all you've been through.
还有别的吗
You got anything else?
现在没了
Not at the moment.
但是一旦有消息  你一定是第一个知道的
But you'll be the first to know when I do.
好了
Okay.
萨尔瓦多的马赛拉的人
Marcella's people in El Salvador
和录像中那两个人的纹身匹配
matched that tattoos in the video to these two guys.
尤万尼·委拉斯开兹  阿隆佐·阿玛亚
Yovani Valasquez, Alonzo Amaya.
是SS-11的帮派人  这是他们的老大
Part of a violent SS-11 clique, led by that guy.
罗欧·马丁尼兹  又叫"老狼"
That's Raul Martinez, AKA "El Lobo."
因为谋杀和其他重罪在我国被通缉
Wanted for murder and other felonies in my country.
我通知了国际刑警  在联调局那里把他们做了标记
I notified Interpol, flagged them with the Feds,
把他们的相貌发给了巡逻队
and put their faces out to patrol.
诱捕行动进行得如何
All right, so where we at with the sting operation?
民防处连到了面包房的音像
OCD's got the bakery wired for video and sound.
凯文和我会在里面烘焙
Kevin and I will be inside, baking.
是的  我们可能在那待一段时间
Yeah, and we'll probably be in there for a while,
因为如果这些家伙聪明的话  他们可能会在
because if these dudes are smart they might lay low
当铺事件之后保持低调
after what they did in the pawn shop, right?
SS-11不会
Not SS-11.
他们会一直去  不停恐吓
They just keep coming, they keep intimidating.
知道了
Copy that.
-在那小心点  -谢谢
- Be careful out there. - Thank you.
饼干  奶酪蛋糕  每日现烤
我看到你没戴婚戒
I didn't see a ring on your finger.
你应该当警探
You should be a detective someday.
是吗
Yeah?
我离婚了
I'm divorced.
但是我们有两个很棒的孩子  一个男孩一个女孩
But we have two great kids, a boy and a girl.
或者应该说是小女人
Or should I say, young woman.
一个非常聪明  顽固的小女人
A very smart, opinionated young woman at that.
女生是很复杂的
Well, girls are complicated.
我注意到了
Yeah, I've noticed.
-你呢  -我复杂吗
- How about you? - Complicated?
我也复杂
Oh, yeah, I am.
结婚了吗
Married.
去年之前我是已婚的
I was, until last year.
看来和在哪当警察无关啊
Guess it doesn't matter where you're a cop, huh?
工作有同样的效果
Job has the same effect?
工作不是问题所在  反正我们之间不是
That wasn't the problem. With us, anyway.
我们的儿子去世了
Our son passed away.
交通事故
Traffic accident.
他才13岁
He was 13 years old,
在那之后一切都分崩离析了
and everything kind of fell apart after that.
我很遗憾
I'm so sorry to hear that.
那不是件易事
Yeah, it's not easy.
是啊
Yeah.
是啊...
Yeah, it's...
-走吧  -好
- Come on. - Yeah.
心理治疗得怎么样
How's therapy going?
我从没想到过我会这么大声说出来  但...
I never thought I'd say this out loud, but...
我其实有点喜欢
I actually kind of like it.
我被惊到了
Wow, I am shocked.
很有用
It's helpful.
终于能处理一下在阿富汗发生的事
Finally dealing with some stuff that happened in Afghanistan.
还有芝加哥
And Chicago.
很高兴听到你这么说
I'm happy to hear it.
小心  生意好像来了
Heads up, we might be in business.
目标进去了
Target went in.
有什么我能帮到你的吗  年轻人
Can I help you, young man?
你这地方很漂亮啊
Pretty nice place you got here.
想继续保持下去吗
Wanna keep it that way?
就得付钱
Gonna have to pay.
我不像这里的其他人
I am not like the other folks around here.
我能搞定我自己的生意
I can take care of my own business.
街角的那死人不愿意付钱
Dead man down the block didn't want to pay.
像你这样的老女人在这会很危险的
Could get real dangerous around here for an old lady like you.
不要恐吓我  小男孩
Don't threaten me, little boy.
-我是小男孩  -别  别  别  妈
- I'm a little boy? - Hey, hey, hey, ma,
把球棒放下  听着
put the bat down. Hey, listen.
我们不想惹麻烦  好吗
We don't want those problems, okay?
-你能出去吗  -你回去
- Can you just get out of here? - You go back,
告诉你老大  我不会给任何人一分钱
and tell your boss that I ain't paying nobody nothing.
快点  兄弟  离开这里
Come on, man, just leave.
给老娘滚出去...
Get your sorry ass out of my store...
这事没完  贱人
This ain't over, bitch!
不然我就像敲碎椰子一样敲碎你的脑壳
Or I will split your skull like a coconut!
干得漂亮  弗兰尼女士
Great job, Ms. Franny.
看到一号人物
I've got number one in pocket,
在18大街向西朝伍德街行进
heading westbound on 18th towards Wood St.
收到  在18大街向西行进  我们跟宝丽娜
Copy, westbound on 18th. We're taking Paulina.
1号给了2号一张纸条
Number one just handed a note to number two.
男性  西班牙裔  拿着滑板
Male, Hispanic, holding a skateboard.
在17大街和18大街之间的过道朝北走
Heading north in the gangway between 17th and 18th.
我需要2号的情况
I need eyes on number two.
去  在下个拐角跟上
Go ahead, take the next corner.
好
Okay.
我跟上2号了
I have number two in pocket.
他在小巷中朝东走  接近宝丽娜
He's moving eastbound in the alley, approaching Paulina.
目标和3号目标有接触
Subject made contact with target number three.
是个女性西班牙裔
It's a female Hispanic,
大概16岁  穿着绿色夹克
about 16 years old, green jacket.
蓝色牛仔裤  深色球鞋
Blue jeans, dark sneakers.
收到  向东接近宝丽娜
Copy, eastbound approaching Paulina.
我跟着二号  继续朝巷子东过去
I have number two, continuing eastbound in the alley.
我看不到
I can't see.
不知道他们有没有交接
I don't know if a handoff was made.
我需要有人盯着三号  他在向北走
I need eyes on number three who's now northbound
在铁轨下面  朝17街过去
under the El, heading towards 17.
我在车里  这就去你那
In the car heading your way.
-我盯着三号  -收到
- I have eyes on number three. - Copy.
跟着她  马赛拉  我这就去你那
Stay with her, Marcella. I'm coming your way.
马赛拉  你在哪  请回答
Marcella, where are you? Please respond.
马赛拉  能听到吗  请回答
Marcella, can you hear me? Please respond.
怎么了
Hey, what's going on?
我跟丢了
I lost her.
-谁进了院子  -我以为那是她
- Who was going into the yard? - Someone I thought was her.
她跟几个骑车的孩子碰了面
She met up with some kids on bikes,
然后他们就分头走了
and they all drove off in different directions.
我不知道她有没有交接
I wasn't sure if she made the handoff,
我刚刚跟丢了
and I lost her for a minute.
我刚才在对讲机上找你
I was calling you on the radio.
我肯定不小心把声音关小了
Oh, I must have turned the volume down by accident.
是的
Yeah.
-有结果吗  -没有  你们呢
- Any luck? - No, you?
他们很难跟
They're tough to follow.
是说啊
That's the whole idea.
现在怎么办
So what now?
等着  看弗兰尼或者说中指的消息
We wait. Franny's message, or should I say middle finger,
会不会传到老大那里
is on its way back to the boss.
我觉得他会有所回应
I'm guessing he's going to respond.
毫无疑问的  问题是什么时候
Yeah, no doubt. The question is when.
是的  会有多少砍刀
Yeah, and with how many machetes.
-你没事吧  -没事
- You all right? - Yes.
我以为你们今天已经收工了
I thought you guys were done for the day.
是的  食物链底层的人
Yeah, well, low man on the totem pole.
必须得有人记录监控信息
Someone has to transcribe the surveillance logs.
反黑组的警探来过
Detective from gang stopped by,
想找那个萨尔瓦多美女
looking for the pretty lady from El Salvador.
他让我确定她收到这个
He asked me to make sure she got that.
你确定不是凶案组的人吗
You sure it wasn't homicide?
她跟反黑组的人没有任何来往
She's not working with anyone from gangs.
是欧伯伦  我认识他
It was O'Brien. I know him.
他很期待跟她见面
He was really looking forward to meeting her in person.
警察啊
Cops.
马赛拉
金·伯吉斯
-抱歉  -你要走了吗
- Sorry about that. - Do you need to go?
不  不  我没事
No, no, I'm fine.
其实  你打电话给我之前
Actually, before you called,
我刚要回那个空空荡荡的家里
I was on my way home to an empty house,
所以这样挺好的
so this is a treat.
我很高兴
Well, it's good to know that
我能打败一座空房子
I can still beat out an empty house.
所以你你刚才再说你有多喜欢单身
So you were telling me about how much you like being single?
是的  特别棒
Mmm, oh yeah, it's fantastic.
我喜欢无拘无束
I love swiping right, or left.
太浪漫了
It's so romantic, you know.
我不太擅长这个
I'm not very good at this.
但是
But...
你想去我房间吗
Do you want to come up to my room?
想去
I'd like to.
但问题是  我应该去吗
But the question is, should I?
我觉得你应该去
I think you should.
你的搭档一直在给你打电话
Your partner's been calling.
办公室见  好吗
See you at the office, okay?
等等  没事吧
Wait, is everything okay?
没事  我挺好的
Yes, I'm fine.
我跟琳德赛聊过
So I talked to Lindsey.
-嗯  -她没事
- Yeah. - She's solid.
他们什么都没拿到
All they got is a bag full of bones.
没事的
This is going to be fine.
只是...
Listen. Just...
你保持警惕  好吗
Keep your ear to the ground, okay?
如果有事  一公里之外我就要知道
If it's coming, I want to see it from a mile away.
好的  不过别担心
All right, but don't worry, man.
你知道我会挺你
You know I got your back.
好吗
All right?
怎么了
What's up?
回我一个电话会比较好
A call back would have been nice.
对不起  什么事这么重要
I'm sorry. What's so important?
我很担心马赛拉
I'm concerned about Marcella.
我觉得她在玩我们
I think she's playing us.
怎么玩我们  什么意思
Playing us how, what do you mean?
我不知道  所以很奇怪
I don't know, that's what's so odd.
金  我很累  我们还有很多工作要做
Kim, I'm tired. We have a lot of work to do.
好吧  我觉得
Okay, um, I think that, uh,
她一直在跟黑帮组的欧伯伦联系
she's been talking to O'Brien from gangs.
-她怎么会认识他  -就是啊
- How does she know him? - Exactly.
我以为她来这里是观察凶案
I thought she was here to observe homicide.
他昨晚把这个留给她
He dropped this off for her last night.
她为什么要通过他查我们的犯人
What the hell is she doing running our offenders through him?
他昨晚本来要跟她见面喝一杯的
And he was supposed to meet her for a drink last night,
但她取消了  所以...
but she cancelled, so...
我猜是有更好的选择
I guess something better came along.
这事你问过欧伯伦吗
You ask O'Brien about this?
也许她在凶案组时跟他打过交道
Maybe she crossed with him when she was working with homicide.
我会打电话给欧伯伦
I have a call into O'Brien.
那就行了  可能是她只是想帮忙
There you go, could be she's just trying to help.
-还有什么需要我知道的吗  -有
- Anything else I need to know? - Yeah.
昨天  我在街上发现马赛拉时
Yesterday, when I found Marcella on the street,
她告诉我她跟丢了那个孩子
she told me she lost the kid she was following.
但我看见她看着一个女孩
But I saw her watch a girl,
和描述的一摸一样
fitting the exact same description
穿过门  进了院子
walk through a gate, into a yard.
非常清楚  我问了她这事
It was clear as day. I asked her about it,
她当着我的面撒了谎
and she lied to my face.
这事她为什么撒谎
Why would she lie about that?
这就是我要说的  安东尼奥  一些事不对劲
That's what I'm talking about Antonio. Something's off.
我不清楚
I don't know.
你和我们反黑组的人聊过了吗
Hey, are you talking to a guy in our gang unit?
是的
Yeah.
基斯·欧伯伦
Keith O'Brien.
我让他帮我们查了SS-11的人
I asked him to run some stuff for us on those SS-11 guys.
怎么了
Why?
他昨晚来了一趟警局
He dropped it off at the district last night.
我知道  他给我发短信了
I know. He texted me.
我该请他喝一杯的  但...
I was supposed to buy him a drink to thank him, but...
当时我有了更棒的邀请
I had a better offer.
你怎么认识他的
How do you know him?
我在重案组的时候认识的
I met him when I was working with homicide.
他给了我自己的名片  告诉我
He gave me his card, told me,
有需要打给他
call me if you ever need anything.
我该通过你们找他的
I should have run it through you guys.
我只是想帮忙  抱歉
I was just trying to help, I'm so sorry.
我明白  没事的
I get it. That's all right.
只是有人很困惑  就这样
Just some people were confused, that's all.
谢谢你见我  基斯
Thanks for meeting me, Keith.
别紧张  像我说的  我就在附近
No sweat, like I said, I was in the neighborhood.
-怎么了  -马赛拉·戈麦斯
- What's up. - Marcella Gomez.
她怎么了
What about her?
她是不是就马克当铺的
Did she ask you to do the work ups
凶杀案和你做了些合作
for the homicide at Marco's pawn shop?
对  有什么问题
Yeah, is there a problem?
没  我只是不清楚
No, I'm just... I don't know,
我只是好奇她怎么有你号码的
I was just wondering how she got your number.
她只是过来一周左右
She's only been here a week or so.
两月前  她从萨尔瓦多过来
Two months ago, she reached out from El Salvador.
想知道罗欧·马丁尼兹  就是"老狼"
Wanted to know about Raul Martinez, "El Lobo."
等等  她两个月前就和你说了"老狼"
Wait, she was talking to you about "El Lobo" two months ago?
对  萨尔瓦多的一个线人告诉她
Yeah, an informant in El Salvador told her
他要去芝加哥
that he was headed to Chicago.
所以我去和我们的线人核实  但没什么收获
So I checked it out with our CI's but came up dry.
为什么  有什么要紧的
Why, what's the big deal?
我不想惹着谁
Look, I'm not trying to step on toes.
她昨天打给我
She called me yesterday,
说碰巧过来培训
said she just happened to be here for training,
和你们的人共事
was working with you guys,
就提到"老狼"这名字
and "El Lobo's" name came up.
好  没什么
Right, no big deal.
谢谢  基斯  我欠你一顿酒
Thanks, Keith. I owe you a beer.
希望越积越多
I intend to collect.
杰
Jay.
大伙  目标出现
Guys, we've got company.
可能目标停到了位置后方
Possible targets pulling up to the rear of the location.
没有车牌
No tags on the vehicle.
目标携带武器  去了烘焙坊的后门
Targets are armed and moving toward the rear door of the bakery.
大家行动
Everybody move.
准备好了吗
All right, ready?
-是的  -好
- Yeah. - Okay.
行动
Let's go.
皮尔森烘焙坊  进货口
我们是芝加哥警署   放下砍刀
Hey, Chicago PD, drop the machete.
放下武器
Put it down!
Put it down.
放下武器
Put it down!
过来
Come on.
起来
All right, get up.
-帮我报告吗  -好
- Call that in for me? - Yeah.
射得漂亮
It was a good shoot.
帽子拿掉
Get rid of that hat.
-干得漂亮  -谢谢
- That's nice work. - Thanks..
另一个罪犯当场死亡
The other offender's DOA.
其他人在审查小组那边接受调查
Rest of the guys are finishing up with the shooting team.
我应该过去吗
I need to be at the scene?
不用  当时射得很有必要
No, it was a good shoot.
监控探头都拍下来了
All caught on our surveillance video.
他们只是要写一下文件
They're just getting the papers straight.
是谁把那孩子培养成那样的
So who tuned the kid up?
他就那样走进了烘焙坊
He walked into the bakery like that.
说真的
I'm serious.
对于一个暴徒而言  阿隆佐很年轻
Alonzo looks pretty young for an enforcer.
在马可谋杀案的录像中
In the video of Marco's murder,
他看上去紧张又害怕
he looks very nervous and scared.
我猜那是他第一次杀人
I'm thinking it was his first kill.
像是帮派入会要求那种吗
Like some kind of gang initiation thing?
没错
Exactly.
那之后  会有个仪式
After that, there's a ceremony.
帮派老人
Senior members of the gang
会痛打他11秒
beat up the chequeo for 11 seconds.
如果他像一个男人一样挨下了痛打
If he takes the beating like a man,
就算入会了
He's in.
无论他有没有像一个男人一样挨下痛打
Whether or not he took the ass-whooping like a man,
他都是个吓坏了的男孩
he's a boy, and he's terrified.
也许从没进过局子
Probably never been in a room before.
那咱们就利用这点
Yeah, so let's use that. You and me.
调查这个"老狼"
Let's find this "El Lobo."
我们知道在当铺发生了什么  阿隆佐
We know what happened at the pawn shop, Alonzo.
探头都拍下来了
We got the whole thing on video.
我觉得
I think...
瓦拉科斯杀了他
Valasquez killed him.
你揍他的时候他已经死了  对吧
He was dead by the time you got your whacks in, right?
他叫马可
His name was Marco.
他曾是我的朋友
He was my friend.
总得有人为此负责
And someone has to pay for that.
现在  那个人就是你
Right now, that someone is you.
看着我  阿隆佐
Look at me, Alonzo.
马可是你杀的第一个人  对不对
Marco was your first, right?
我就知道
Yeah, I thought so.
我猜猜
Let me guess.
你肯定希望你没杀他吧
You wish you hadn't done it, right?
希望一切可以重来
Wish you could take it back.
-没错  -可是...
- I do. - Yeah, well...
谋杀就是这样
See, that's the thing about murder.
永远无法重来
You can't take it back.
它会折磨你一辈子
It stays with you the rest of your life.
无论你多努力想要摆脱它
No matter how hard you try.
你多大了  阿隆佐
How old are you, Alonzo?
16吗
Sixteen?
我知道说这话你可能不信
I know it doesn't seem like it right now,
但你这辈子还长着呢
but you got your whole life ahead of you.
只要你能走正道
If you play your cards right.
孩子  现在这房间里发生的一切
Son, what happens in this room right now.
现在的一切
Right now.
将决定你是会老死在监狱里
Determines...if you die in prison an old man...
还是能在25岁前就刑满释放
Or you walk free by your 25th birthday.
你只需要告诉我们"老狼"在哪里
And all you've got to do is tell us where "El Lobo" is.
你准备怎么做
So what's it going to be?
昨晚
Last night,
"老狼"睡在了索耶街的一栋房子里
"El Lobo" slept in a house on a street called Sawyer.
索耶街挺大的  是在附近  还是就在那里
Okay, Sawyer's a big street. Near it, on it?
在一个街角
It was on a corner.
是蓝色的
Um, it was blue.
街对面还有中餐馆
There was Chinese across the street.
附近还有什么
What else was around there?
中餐馆旁边还有家杂货店
There was a grocery across the street next to the Chinese.
好像是在一个消防局旁边
I think it was near a firehouse.
你确定他周六住在了那里
You're sure he stayed there on Saturday?
确定
Yeah.
你在想什么  警探
Is there something on your mind, Detective?
-可他现在应该已经走了  -嗯
- But he could be gone by now. - Yeah.
你昨天说你把孩子跟丢了是在撒谎
You lied about losing the kid you were following yesterday.
我看见她走进了那栋房子
I saw her walk into that building,
也看见你看着她走进了那栋房子
and I saw you see her walk into that building.
我已经解释过了
I already explained that.
你两个月前就知道"老狼"会来芝加哥
You knew "El Lobo" was gonna be in Chicago two months ago.
你到底为什么要撒谎  马赛拉
Why would you lie about that, Marcella?
失陪一下
Excuse me.
-亚当  -我收到照片了
- Adam? - Yeah, I got the photo.
你能不能对他进行面部识别
Can you run facial rec on that guy?
好  怎么回事
Yeah, what's this about?
那个人刚刚接走了马赛拉
That guy just picked up Marcella.
算了  你就直接查吧
You know what, can you just run it,
我等下再跟你解释
and then I'll explain everything later?
没问题  我看看能查到什么
Of course. I'll see what I can find.
谢了
Thank you.
好了好了好了
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
快点快点快点
Come on, come on, come on.
萨尔瓦多警探未成年之子遭SS-11谋杀
我操
Holy crap.
怎么了
What?
马赛拉的儿子被"老狼"谋杀了
Marcella's son was murdered by "El Lobo."
我也不想这么说  可这样就说得通了
Well, I hate to say it, but that actually makes sense.
怎么说得通
How does that make sense?
这件事根本不可能说得通
Nothing about this makes any sense.
你看这个人  这就是接她走的那个人
Check this guy out, this was the guy that picked her up.
-然后呢  -他叫弗朗西斯科·弗洛雷斯
- Yeah? - That's Francisco Flores. Right?
是萨尔瓦多义警敢死队"黑手乐队"
Francisco Flores is part of a Salvadoran vigilante death squad
中的一员
called Mano Negra.
他们的主要人物就是暗杀SS-11的老大
Their whole thing is they assassinate SS-11 bosses.
他们来芝加哥就是要杀"老狼"
They're here in Chicago to kill "El Lobo."
杰  你查到索耶街的地址了吗
Jay, you got that address on Sawyer Street?
还在查
I'm working on it.
来看看这个
You need to see this.
马赛拉的儿子被人谋杀了
Marcella's son was murdered?
被人捅死了
Stabbed to death for looking
就因为他看了SS-11的一个成员
at an SS-11 member the wrong way.
她一直在耍我
She's been playing me.
她耍的是我们所有人
She's been playing us.
她来芝加哥不是为了观察谋杀
She didn't come to Chicago to observe homicide.
她来是为了杀"老狼"  安东尼奥
She came to kill "El Lobo," Antonio.
杀人  你怎么知道的
Kill? How do you know that?
因为她一直在和这个男人一起
Because she has been running around town
满城乱转
with this guy.
弗朗西斯科·弗洛雷斯
Francisco Flores.
他是一个专为谋杀SS-11老大的
He's the leader of a Salvadorian hit squad
萨尔瓦多突击小队
that kills SS-11 leaders.
"黑手乐队"的头儿
El Mano Negra
他们不止是杀人
They don't just kill.
还会严刑拷打  有时候可能长达数日
They also engage in torture. Sometimes for days.
我查到地址了  索耶街1235号
I got the address, 1235 Sawyer Street.
是一栋蓝色的房子  对面是
It's a blue house across the street
吴家中餐馆和洛佩兹杂货店
from Wu's Chinese Restaurant, and Lopez Groceria.
房子的主人叫瓜达卢佩·迪亚兹
House is owned by Guadalupe Diaz.
-有两个孩子  -好了  我们出发
- She's got two young kids. - All right, let's hit it.
50-21C  紧急情况
50-21, Charlie, emergency.
有人倒地  胸部连中数枪
Man down, multiple gunshot wounds to the chest.
收到  21-70
Copy that, 21-70.
-准备好了吗  -嗯
- Ready? - Yeah.
不许动
Don't move!
没事的没事的  你们安全了
It's okay. It's okay. You're safe.
警长  血迹在这里就消失了
Well, Sarge, the blood trail stops right here.
也许当时车就停在这里
Maybe this is where the car was parked.
嗯  看来有人伤的很重
Yeah, someone's leaking pretty bad.
和我们想的一样
It's what we thought.
马赛拉和她的搭档弗洛雷斯
Marcella and her partner, Flores,
比我们早十分钟赶来了这里
busted in ten minutes before we got here.
他们杀了卧室的人
They killed the guy in the living room,
绑了"老狼"
handcuffed "El Lobo,"
把他带到后面塞进了后备箱
Took him out back and put him in the trunk.
那些血是哪来的
Where's all the fresh blood coming from?
她认为弗洛雷斯也中枪了
Well, she thinks Flores was shot, too.
她看到他倚着车  捂着肚子
She saw him leaning against the car, holding his stomach.
好  找当地医院和诊所  寻找枪伤患者
All right, check local hospitals and clinics for gunshot victims.
对马赛拉和弗洛雷斯发出通缉
Put a BOLO out on Marcella and Flores.
-收到  -马上标记他们的护照
- Copy that. - Flag their passports with TSA, now.
好的  谢谢
Yeah, got it. Thanks.
好  目前什么情况
Okay, what do we got?
诊所和医院没有消息
The clinics and hospitals are negative.
她的护照标记了  也发出了通缉
TSA flagged her passport, we have a BOLO out,
我们已经尽量把出城的每条路都盯着了
and every way out of the city covered the best we can.
"老狼"的尸体还没出现
"El Lobo's" body hasn't turned up yet,
所以还有可能
so there's still a chance
他们仍然在什么地方折磨他
they're here torturing him somewhere.
查到了马赛拉的电话记录
Yo, we got into Marcella's phone records.
她来芝加哥后  就用她的手机
Since she's been in Chicago, she's made about a dozen calls
跟这一一次性手机通话无数次
from her phone to this burner phone
这部手机应该是弗洛雷斯的
that we're assuming belongs to Flores.
弗洛雷斯的一次性手机没信号了  但技术人员
The Flores burner's dead, but OCD was able to recreate
利用信号数据从之前的呼出通话中
a digital trail using signal data
查到了数据线索
from his previous outgoing calls.
所有通话都是从南希尔兹三个地址中的一个呼出的
Those calls originated from one of three homes on South Shields.
金  能查一下这些地址吗
Kim, can you run these addresses?
-好  -南希尔兹5220号  5222号  5226号
- Yeah. - 5220, 22, 26 South Shields.
好  5220号是一个单亲家庭
Okay, 5220 is a single family home.
房主是托马斯·米勒
Owned by Thomas Miller.
他从1967年开始就一直交税
He's been paying taxes since 1967.
5222号的房主是玛利亚·瓦尔迪兹
Then there's 5222, Maria Valdez owns it.
她在那里住了10年了
She's lived there 10 years.
5226号
5226...
是空的
is vacant.
就是那里  我们行动
That's the one. Let's hit it.
-右边  -好
- Go right. - Yeah.
马赛拉  把枪放下
Marcella, put the gun down.
放下武器
Drop your weapon!
退后  否则我杀了他
Step back, or I'm going to kill him.
不要  马赛拉  不值得
Don't do this, Marcella. It's not worth it.
当然值
Sure it is.
马赛拉  他会为对你儿子做出的事付出代价
Marcella, he's going to pay for what he did to your son.
他的生命已经结束了
His life's already over.
你扣动扳机的话你的也结束了
You pull that trigger, your life is over too.
快把枪放下
Now put the gun down.
他杀了我儿子那天我就死了
I died the day he killed my son.
但是杀了他不会让你儿子死而复生
But killing him is not going to bring your boy back.
不会让你再次完整  相信我
It won't make you whole again. Believe me.
把枪给我
Give me the gun.
听他的  把枪放下
Do what he says. Put it down.
退后  退后
Step back! Step back!
马赛拉  把枪给我
Marcella, give me the gun.
警长  警长  警长
Sarge, Sarge, Sarge.
马赛拉
Marcella.
把枪放...
Put the gun dow--
对不起
I'm so sorry.
没事了  没事
It's all right. It's okay.
她还有呼吸对吧
I think she's still breathing, right?
5021D  紧急情况
5021 David, emergency.
嫌犯和警方都开枪
Shots fired at the offender and the police.
你不会有事吧
You going to be okay?
抱歉
Hey, I'm sorry.
你是对的
You were right.
我分心了
I was distracted.
你只是在照顾我
You were just looking out for me.
当一个好搭档
Being a good partner.
已死亡
她为任务而来
She was on a mission.
相信我
Trust me.
不论你说什么  都无法阻止她的
There's nothing you could have said would have stopped her.
已死亡
唯一支撑她的就是那份恨
Only thing kept her going was that hate.
-你做了你该做的  -嗯
- You did what you had to do. - Yeah.
是她想让我做的
What she wanted me to do.
汉克
Hank.
你真是个喜欢习惯的人
You truly are a creature of habit, my man.
在杰克酒吧喝一杯威士忌  看老鹰队比赛
A scotch, and a Hawks game at Jack's.
给我一杯波本  再给我的朋友来杯威士忌
Uh, bourbon for me, another scotch for my friend.
不用了
I'm good.
你可能会再想喝一杯
You might want to have another one.
你想干什么  丹尼
What do you want, Denny?
实验室找到了一枚变形的子弹
Well, the lab recovered a deformed slug.
从宾汉姆尸体附近的土里
From the soil around Bingham's body.
虽然变形严重
I mean, it was in pretty bad shape
毕竟在土里埋了那么久
after being in the ground all this time,
但是现如今科学技术突飞猛进了  汉克
but science has come a long way since we started out, Hank.
化验室的人能让你刮目相看
Those folks in the crime lab can do amazing things.
谢谢
Thank you.
调查之后发现
Well, it turns out...
那枚子弹跟几年前一起
That slug matches a round that was recovered
向警察开枪的
at the scene of an armed robbery
持械抢劫案中发现的子弹一致
where shots were fired at police a few years back.
而且
And, turns out...
当时是你去抓的犯人
That you made the arrest.
但是疑犯的枪一直没找到
But the suspect's gun was never recovered.
就快了  汉克
We're getting closer, Hank.
在我看来  只是时间问题了
Way I see it, just a matter of time.
你看比分
Oh, look at that score.
看来这场比赛快结束了
Looks like this game is just about over.
再见  汉克
We'll see you, Hank.